<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Missions>
  <Mission ID="1" Name="There's gold in them there hills">
    <Description>There is a rumour going around about a cache of equipment stashed away in a remote area. Your unit
    is in dire need of extra supplies and ammunition. So while the information may be just another red herring, the
    opportunity is just too good to pass up.
    </Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>
        Seems you're not the only one to believe... There is a lot of activity in the surrounding areas
        of the area indicated by the rumours... Better get in and get out as quick as you can. Things might get ugly.
      </Briefing>
      <Setup>
        Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.        
        This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".        
      </Setup>
      <Objective>
      Objective is to find the cache of weapons and to get them off the home edge. In order to collect the cache
      you must have at least one unit capable of carrying cargo. 
      See ("Battlemech Lifting Capabilities" [TW-261] and "Cargo Carriers" [TW-261]). 
      In the event you do not have a mech with this prerequisite then you cannot fulfil the mission and must retreat.
      </Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
        Locate the cache, extract the cache and exit off the home map edge. The cache represents a significant financial
        boost to your unit, but isn't worth the world. 
        The attacker loses the mission in the event:
          Two or more attacking units are disabled/destroyed.
          20 turns are completed without the cache being removed from the board. (If all cache markers are searched and
          there is no cache found then the attacker must exit the home edge before the end of turn 30.)
          If the cache is not found and there are cache markers unsearched remaining on the map.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
        Any of your units the exit any map edge other than the home edge specified in the Setup section are considered 
        destroyed. As there are a significant number of other units in the area they will be ambushed and wiped out. 
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes>
        When the attacking player moves a unit into the hex containing a cache marker he may spend a firing phase searching
        the hiding spot for the loot. During this firing phase the searching unit must not fire weapons or make any physical
        attacks.
        Additionally, the searching unit is interrupted by the following:
        A successful physical attack against the searching unit.
        A critical hit that destroys a critical location on the searching unit.

        The number on the marker represents the target number for a roll to determine if that marker represents the
        cache. When a cache marker is successfully searched, a single D6 is rolled. If the number is greater than
        or equal to the number on the cache marker then the cache has been discovered. As soon as the cache is
        discovered, all other markers are removed.
      </Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>Someone has been talking too much... A rumour mill has started up about your weapons cache.
      Now the hills for miles around are crawling with opportunists and treasure hunters... Maybe if you're lucky
      they might just all pass you by... Maybe... then again, your luck hasn't been that great of late. If only your
      Commander had told you where the crate is concealed then you might have been able to defend it properly... Then again,
      perhaps he figured you might just carry it off yourself...
      </Briefing>
      <Setup>
        The defending player places each(6) of the cache markers in a location on Map 2.
        The markers must not be placed in the open unless it is not possible to place them otherwise.
        The markers must not be placed in terrain prohibited to Battlemech movement.
        There must be at least two intervening hexes between markers.
        The markers are placed with the number written on the marker face down.
        The attacking player should not see the numbers on the counters when they are placed. In addition, The
        defender MAY NOT examine the markers once they are placed.
        The defending units are setup as per hidden setup (TW-259). The units may or may not be located in the same
        hexes as the cache markers.
      </Setup>
      <Objective>
        Your objectives are two-fold. Firstly to defend the cache against the attacking unit. Secondly once the
        attacker has been beaten off, to search the remaining caches (if any) and remove the loot for yourself.
        No cache counter can be searched while any functional attacking unts remain on the maps.
        See ("Battlemech Lifting Capabilities" [TW-261] and "Cargo Carriers" [TW-261]).
      </Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
        The Defender loses the mission in the following cases.
          If the attacker successfully removes the cache.
          If 50% or more of the defending units are disabled or destroyed.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
        Defending Units may retreat off Map 2 Edge 2. These units are counted as retreated and not destroyed but may 
        not return for the duration of the game. They are also counted as losses for victory condition purposes.
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1.25</ForceRatio>
    <Notes>The cache contains 250,000 CBills</Notes>
  </Mission>
  <Mission ID="2" Name="Street Fight">
    <Description>You have gained a reputation as a street fighter... well, someone is calling you out...</Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>The local area has a lot going for it in the way of businesses willing to support your unit
      with employment opportunities... You are keen to take advantage of that but it seems someone else in
      the area has the same ideas... Time to defend "your" turf...
      </Briefing>
      <Setup>      
      Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. 
      Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.        
      This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".</Setup>
      <Objective>Control the battlefield. There must be no active enemy units left on the maps</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>If the attacking player controls the maps at the end of the game, then the attacker is victorious.</VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions></SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>The local area has a lot going for it in the way of businesses willing to support your unit
      with employment opportunities... You are keen to take advantage of that but it seems someone else in
      the area has the same ideas... Time to defend "your" turf...</Briefing>
      <Setup>Defender forces enter on turn one. 
      Entry is from Edge 2 of Map 2. Valid entry hexes are from 1501 to 1517.        
      This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".
      </Setup>
      <Objective>Control the battlefield. There must be no active enemy units left on the maps</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>If the defending player controls the maps at the end of the game, then the defender is victorious.</VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions></SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1</ForceRatio>
    <Notes>By establishing itself as the dominant force in the area, the winner receives 300,000 CBills as a contract retainer from the local businesses.</Notes>
  </Mission>
  <Mission ID="3" Name="A Ransom is offered...">
    <Description>Militia forces have captured a local politician and are asking a ransom for his return. You have been engaged to return the politician safely, and eliminate the militia unit.</Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>
      You have been hired by the planetary government to extract a hostage from militia forces holding them hostage.
      The hostage is an important local politician and must be returned alive.
      </Briefing>
      <Setup>Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.        
        This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".
        </Setup>
      <Objective>The attackers must locate the hostage and extract them from the map. The unit carrying the
      hostage must exit off the player home edge.</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      The scenario is a victory if the hostage is rescued and carried safely off the attacking players home edge. 
      Any other result is a loss.
      If the hostage is returned safely, the attacker receives 300,000 CBills as payment.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
      The hostage is a single individual hidden in a building on Map 2. The hostage will exit the building 
      of their own accord provided there are no active enemy units within 6 hexes or line of sight to the building.
      If the unit carrying the hostage is destroyed, place the hostage as per an ejected pilot. (see - TO-196) The hostage
      takes a single point of damage and must roll for consciousness.
      An unconscious hostage may be picked up by a unit with a functioning hand actuator and may be carried. If the 
      hostage is carried in this manner then the unit carrying the hostage may not Run, Jump or go Prone. In addition,
      if the unit falls, then the hostage takes 2 points of damage and is placed as per an ejecting pilot (TO-196)
      If the building containing the hostage is destroyed, then the hostage is killed. 
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>Looks like the simple grab and run job isn't going to be so simple after all. Seems
      the person you're "looking after" is fairly important and their presence is missed more than
      you were lead to believe it would be...</Briefing>
      <Setup>
      A light single story building is placed on each of the following hexes on Map 2 [MAPHEXES-2]. 
      The defending player secretly notes which building the hostage is located in.
      If there are no defending units within 6 hexes, or line of sight of the building containing the hostage 
      then the hostage may reveal their presence to the attacking forces.
      The defending player may setup hidden (TW-259).
      </Setup>
      <Objective>Objective is to keep the hostage secure.</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>The scenario is a loss if the hostage is rescued and carried safely off the attacking players home edge. 
      The scenario is also a loss if the hostage is killed. 
      Any other result is a victory.
      If the scenario is a victory, the defending player receives 500,000 CBills as payment.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
      If the building containing the hostage is destroyed, then the hostage is killed.
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1.25</ForceRatio>
    <Notes>
    </Notes>
  </Mission>
  <Mission ID="4" Name="Things that go bump in the night">
    <Description>Folks are getting jittery... someone is making trouble in the local area and no one seems
    to be able to stop them....</Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>You've been contracted to disrupt the local law enforcement agencies. So far you've been
      very successful at routing out beat cops and hired muscle and sending them packing... the anti has just been upped however...
      If you can make merry for one more day, your benefactor has promised much in the way of rewards...</Briefing>
      <Setup>
      Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. 
      Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.        
      This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".
      The attacker places 6 light single story buildings (Light CF10 - See (Buildings TW-167) on the following hexes on Map 1 [MAPHEXES-1] 
      </Setup>
      <Objective>The objective is to destroy as many of the 12 buildings as possible</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>The attacker gets 25,000 CBills for each building destroyed</VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>The local authority has had enough of a rebel force in the area disrupting local forces.
      The population is frightened and someone needs to come in to exercise some control. They've hired you
      to seek out the troublemakers and send them packing.</Briefing>
      <Setup>
      Defender forces enter on turn one. 
      Entry is from Edge 2 of Map 2. Valid entry hexes are from 1501 to 1517.        
      This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".
      The defender places 6 light single story buildings (Light CF10 - See (Buildings TW-167) on the following hexes on Map 2 [MAPHEXES-2] 
      </Setup>
      <Objective>The objective is to save as many of the 12 buildings as possible.</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>The defender gets 25,000 CBills for each building not destroyed</VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions></SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1</ForceRatio>
    <Notes>
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 2500 and less than 3000 then the Buildings all become Light - BF15
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 3000 and less than 4000 then the Buildings all become Medium - BF20
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 4000 then the Buildings all become Heavy - BF30
    </Notes>
  </Mission>
  <Mission ID="5" Name="Where angels fear to tread">
    <Description>A militia group has set up camp in the area. They've managed to fortify their camp
    so that all the local authorities have failed to move them...</Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>You've been contracted to remove a militia group from the local area. They have
      setup a fortified camp defended by emplaced weapons and ringed with a fence. Your job is to destroy
      the fortified camp and eliminate or drive off all the militia units...
      </Briefing>
      <Setup>Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. 
      Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.        
      This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".</Setup>
      <Objective>Destroy the camp, including all weapon emplacements and wall sections.</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      If all enemy units are eliminated or retreated and all emplaced weapons are destroyed then the scenario is a victory.
      Any other result is a loss.
      The attacking unit gets 250,000 CBills for a victory.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions></SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>"Hold tight...". Those were the words your commanding officer left you with. So far the locals
      have done everything they can to move you on. Somehow though, you think the worst is far from over.
      </Briefing>
      <Setup>
      The defending player has 6 emplaced weapons. 
      These are placed in Medium CF-15 (See Buildings TW-167) buildings as turrets on the following hexes on Map 2 [MAPHEXES-2].
      Buildings are 2 levels high and block line of sight.
      They have 360 degree fire arcs and contain a single Autocannon/5.
      Each turret contains 30 rounds of ammunition. Ammunition must be tracked during the scenario.
      Walls are placed between each of the 6 buildings to form a perimeter. 
      The walls must be placed in such a way that they form a single enclosed area.
      One section of wall must be designated as a gate. 
      Units may only enter or exit the enclosed area via the gate unless a wall segment is destroyed.
      Wall segments are 2 levels high and block line of sight.
      The walls are treated as Medium CF-10 buildings.
      The defending units are setup as per hidden setup (TW-259).
      The defending units may NOT be placed in the same hex as a building. 
      </Setup>
      <Objective>The defenders objective is to survive and be in control of the battlefield at the end of the game.</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      The defender must have an active unit remaining on the board at the end of the game. 
      Any other result is a loss. 
      The emplaced weapons do not count as active units.
      The defending unit gets 300,000 CBills for a victory.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>Defending Units may retreat off Map 2 Edge 2. These units are counted as retreated and not destroyed but may 
        not return for the duration of the game. They are also counted as losses for victory condition purposes.
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1.5</ForceRatio>
    <Notes>
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 2500 and less than 3000 then the emplaced Weapons are upgraded to LRM 10s with 30 rounds of ammunition.
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 3000 and less than 4000 then the emplaced Weapons are upgraded to LRM 15s with 25 rounds of ammunition.
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 4000 then the emplaced Weapons are upgraded to PPCs with no heat buildup.
    </Notes>
  </Mission>
  <Mission ID="6" Name="I swear I put that down just over there...">
    <Description>Uh oh... the box you were transporting has just gone missing...</Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>300 grand! That's what you were promised on safe delivery of the 'product'. Now its gone missing but you've tracked the thieves down... Better get a move on... 
      Damned thing is due for delivery today and no show, no cash...</Briefing>
      <Setup>
      Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. 
      Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.
      Map Edge 2 of Map 2 counts as the player home edge. Valid exit hexes are from 1501 to 1517. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".</Setup>
      <Objective>You have 30 turns to eliminate all enemy forces</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      If all enemy forces are eliminated by turn 30 then it is a victory. 
      If any enemy units are alive at the end of Turn 30, you lose.
      The attacker receives 300,000 CBills for a Victory.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>
      Looks like your intel was on the money this time... Right place, right box... Now you just have to get it to the fence and collect the cash.... 
      Ah crap... looks like you've been made... run!
      </Briefing>
      <Setup>
      Defender forces enter on turn one. 
      Entry is from Edge 2 of Map 2. Valid entry hexes are from 1501 to 1517.        
      Map Edge 4 of Map 1 counts as the player home edge. Valid exit hexes are from 0101 to 0117. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".</Setup>
      <Objective>Stay alive for 30 turns.</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      If all your forces are eliminated by turn 30 then it is a loss. 
      If any of your units are alive at the end of Turn 30, you win.
      The defender receives 200,000 CBills for a Victory. 
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions></SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1.1</ForceRatio>
    <Notes>Forces may not leave the map from any other edge than their home edge.</Notes>
  </Mission>
  <Mission ID="7" Name="Serial number, serial killer">
    <Description>
    Alright, listen up, people. 
    Our fugitive has been on the run for ninety minutes. 
    Average foot speed over uneven ground barring injuries is 4 miles-per-hour. 
    That gives us a radius of six miles. 
    What I want from each and every one of you is a hard-target search of every gas station, residence, warehouse, farmhouse, henhouse, outhouse and doghouse in that area. 
    Checkpoints go up at fifteen miles. 
    Your fugitive's name is Aristotle Jones. 
    Go get him.    
    </Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>You have a wanted man on the loose, go get him.</Briefing>
      <Setup>Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.        
        This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".</Setup>
      <Objective>
      Capture the fugitive, dead or alive.
      </Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>If the fugitive is dead or captured by the end of the game, the attacker wins.
      Any other result is a loss.
      The attacker gets 200,000 CBills for a victory.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>Your contact wants you keep this guy alive... he won't say why, but he is talking with his wallet...</Briefing>
      <Setup>
      A light single story building (Light CF10 - See (Buildings TW-167) is placed on each of the following hexes on Map 2 [MAPHEXES-2].
      The defending player secretly notes which building the fugitive is located in.
      The defending PlayerBriefing sets anywhere up on Map 2 except in the buildings.
      The defending player may NOT setup hidden (TW-259).
      Map Edge 2 of Map 2 counts as the player home edge. Valid exit hexes are from 1501 to 1517. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".
      </Setup>
      <Objective>Keep the fugitive alive.</Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      The fugitive must be alive and not captured by an enemy unit at the end of the game for a defender victory.
      The defender gets 300,000 CBills for a victory.
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
      If the building the fugitive is located in is destroyed then the fugitive is killed. The fugitive may 
      leave the building they are concealed in. If this is the case treat them as an ejected pilot for movement
      and combat purposes. (TO-196) 
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1.1</ForceRatio>
    <Notes>
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 2500 and less than 3000 then the Buildings all become Light - BF15
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 3000 and less than 4000 then the Buildings all become Medium - BF20
      If the combined BV of the attacking units is greater than 4000 then the Buildings all become Heavy - BF30
    </Notes>
  </Mission>
  <Mission ID="8" Name="Look what I found.">
    <Description>We attack the target tomorrow... accurate intel is of paramount importance... Don't come back till you know what we face...</Description>
    <MapSet Maps="2" Rows="1" Columns="2" />
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Attacker">
      <Briefing>As a prelude to a night attack a larger unit has engaged your services to scout the intended target and report what you find.</Briefing>
      <Setup>Attacker forces enter on turn one. Entry is from Edge 4 of Map 1. 
      Valid entry hexes are from 0101 to 0117.        
      This map edge also counts as the player home edge. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".</Setup>
      <Objective>
      The attacker must stand a unit on each of the following hexes [MAPHEXES-2].
      The attacker does not tell the defender which hexes he has to scout. 
      The unit must end its movement on one of the target hexes in order for the hex to count as 'scouted'
      The scenario ends at the end of 16 turns.
      As a hex is 'scouted' the attacker announces to the defender and reveals which hex is it.
      </Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      For each successfully 'scouted' hex, the attacker receives 50,000 CBills
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions></SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <PlayerBriefing Team="Defender">
      <Briefing>Something big is brewing in your sector... you don't know what it is but you need to deny the enemy any knowledge of your force deployment.</Briefing>
      <Setup>
      The defending units are setup anywhere on Map 2.
      The defending units are setup as per hidden setup (TW-259).
      Map Edge 2 of Map 2 counts as the player home edge. Valid exit hexes are from 1501 to 1517. See "Movement and Retreat - TW-257".
      </Setup>
      <Objective>Deny the attacker knowledge of the local area. Attempt to ascertain which hexes the 
      attacker is attempting to scout and stop them scouting them
      </Objective>
      <VictoryConditions>
      For each hex not 'scouted', the defender receives 50,000 CBills
      </VictoryConditions>
      <SpecialConditions>
      </SpecialConditions>
      <Notes></Notes>
    </PlayerBriefing>
    <ForceRatio>1.2</ForceRatio>
    <Notes></Notes>
  </Mission>

</Missions>